# Josepp Benvenuto

joseppbenvenuto@gmail.com | 416-618-6761 | 650 Woodbine Ave, M4E 2J1 linkedin.com/in/joseppbenvenuto | joseppbenvenuto.netlify.app | github.com/joseppbenvenuto

#### **PERSONAL STATEMENT**

After turning down a hockey scholarship I couldn't afford, I knew it was time to dive into a new passion. Data. Now, a boot camp and a Data Analytics diploma later, I'm a highly motivated and result-oriented data analyst with two years of experience working with data. Plus, with over five years of financial analysis experience, including open market investments and consumer banking, I have the industry-relevant and transferrable skills that allow me to bring immediate and strategic value to my next opportunity.

#### **SKILLS**

- **Programming Languages:** Python, R, MySQL, PostgreSQL, SAS
- Machine Learning: Python (eg. scikit-learn, nltk, surprise, numpy, pandas, matplotlib), R, SAS
- Miscellaneous Technologies & Skills: A/B testing, Data science pipeline (cleaning, wrangling, visualization, modeling, interpretation), Statistics, Time series, Experimental design, Hypothesis testing, APIs, Microsoft Excel, Microsoft Power BI, Tableau, Microsoft PowerPoint, Sales, Financial analysis

## **PROJECTS**

- <u>Company Cluster Analysis:</u> Clustered 1,613 publicly traded companies in the U.S using their 20-year historical balance sheet, income statement, and stock price data to aid in the exploration of stock-picking criteria and strategy. **Technologies:** Python, R
- NHL Regression and Classification Analysis: Analyzed NHL team season stats for years 1983 2020 to help improve season and playoff outcomes via regression and classification. **Technologies:** Python, R
- <u>S&P 500 Index Analysis:</u> Analyzed risk and return of the S&P 500 Index over the course of four decades for potential capital allocation via A/B testing. **Technologies:** Python

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

### Remote Volunteer Research & Evaluation Analyst | HomeFront

Dec 2019 - Present, Calgary, AB

- Created ad hoc visualizations to present to stakeholders in Tableau
- Explored and cleaned data to complete analytical tasks in Microsoft Excel and Python
- Created custom formatting tools to increase task efficiency and now used widely in the company in Microsoft Excel
- Provided technical support and consultation to peers to increase efficiency and apply best practices regarding data analysis approaches

#### Client Advisor | Royal Bank of Canada

Apr 2018 - Mar 2019 Mississauga, ON

- Analyzed client account data to fulfill their financial needs and better their financial positions to create value for clients and RBC
- Delivered exceptional customer service through a focus on having a growth mindset
- Worked with retirement planners and mortgage specialists to deliver a valuable product mix to clientele
- Achieved an above-average 2.4 million dollars in annual sales volume (Apr 18 Mar 19)
- Adhered to KYC and AML procedures and alike
- Completed the Canadian Securities Course (CSC), Investment Funds in Canada (IFC), Personal Financial Services Advice (PFSA) certifications

#### **EDUCATION**

### Toronto School of Management | Diploma Co-op, Data Analytics

Jun 2020 - Present, Toronto, ON

# Thinkful | Certificate, Remote Data Analytics

Jun 2019 - 2019, Brooklyn, NY

#### Sheridan College | Associate's Degree, Business Marketing

Sep 2014 - 2015, Mississauga, ON

# **ACTIVITIES AND HONORS**

- Received NCAA hockey scholarship offers to Manhattanville College and New England College
- Assistant baseball coach for the U13 Fieldhouse Pirates organization
- To date, I have five years of experience managing the bulk of my family's net worth in public stock markets and for five years (apart from the recent correction due to COVID-19), I continued to beat the S&P 500 Index (average)